<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Super Duper Paratrooper Website]]></title>
  <link href="http://jimothyGator.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jimothyGator.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-02T12:13:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://jimothyGator.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jim Cushing]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rules for Automating Manual Tasks]]></title>
    <link href="http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/07/24/rules-for-automating-manual-tasks/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-24T21:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/07/24/rules-for-automating-manual-tasks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As software developers, we face this dilemna constantly: Should we take the time to automate this repetive task,
or will we be better off slogging through it manually? Having pondered this many times myself, I have developed
the following rules for dealing with this decision:</p>

<ol>
<li>You cannot know how long it will take to manually perform a task until you have already done it.</li>
<li>You cannot know how long it will take to automate a task until you have already automated it.</li>
<li>The second or third time you have to manually perform the same task, you&rsquo;ll curse yourself for not automating it.</li>
<li>After spending hours or days working to automate the task, you will have forgotten why you needed to perform the task if the first place, then curse yourself for not just doing it by hand.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PowerPoint Is "Real Work"]]></title>
    <link href="http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/06/01/powerpoint-is-real-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T12:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/06/01/powerpoint-is-real-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of a man&rsquo;s inescapable responsibilities to his significant other is the trip to the shopping mall. While I was fulfilling my duty to my girlfriend, we passed by the Microsoft Store, and she did a double-take. &ldquo;Wait a minute, isn&rsquo;t the Apple Store upstairs?&rdquo; she asked as she looked in the shop with white walls and evenly spaced tables with computers and gadgets on display. A Microsoft Store does, surely by no coincidence, closely resemble an Apple Store. But there are at least two obvious differences.</p>

<p>One is the four color logo out front. The second is that the Microsoft Store had few customers, in contrast to what is, at this mall at least, a perpetually packed Apple Store. There had to be at least twice as many employees as customers, and maybe three times as many.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s go in,&rdquo; she said.</p>

<p>Let me tell you a little bit about my girlfriend. When it comes to computers and technology, she&rsquo;s just an ordinary person. She has and enjoys her iPhone and iPad. But she has, until very recently, always used Windows computers, and at the time of the visit, she hadn&rsquo;t yet gotten her first Mac<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Windows is the default choice for most people, and she was no different. She doesn&rsquo;t think or care too much about operating system choices, or the companies that make them.</p>

<p>In other words, she&rsquo;s like the majority of people out there, rather than a geek opinionated about technology. That&rsquo;s my role to play in the relationship.</p>

<p>I point this out because what she did next was, honestly, quite geeky.</p>

<p>The Microsoft Store had on display, towards the front of the store, a Windows tablet; I believe it was a Samsung. This was before the release of Windows 8, so it was Windows 7 running on a touch screen. It seemed an odd fit, as the controls controls were not sized with fingers in mind, but it also came with a stylus, so if Windows is your thing, and you want a touch screen, I suppose you could make this work.</p>

<p>A salesperson in a brightly colored t-shirt with a lanyard around his neck (hmm, I swear I&rsquo;ve seen this look before) approached. &ldquo;May I help you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Which is better,&rdquo; my better half asks, &ldquo;this or an iPad?&rdquo;</p>

<p>As I mentioned, she already has an iPad, so this can mean only one thing: She&rsquo;s trolling at the Microsoft Store. Uh oh.</p>

<p>The salesperson starts his spiel, which I honestly didn&rsquo;t pay much attention to, because though I was surprised and somewhat amused by her trolling, I decided it was best I not take a part in it. This could only turn into a mall re-enactment of a million pointless Internet arguments, and I was not in the mood.</p>

<p>She let him continue, an I recall him saying things like &ldquo;real computer&rdquo; and &ldquo;full Windows experience.&rdquo; Then she turned to me and asked, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know, honey, what do you think I should get?&rdquo; She knew what I thought. Definitely trolling.</p>

<p>Oh boy. My effort to stay out of this was being put to the test. &ldquo;Well, honey, you know what I prefer, but you do what you think is best for you.&rdquo; I tried my best at a diplomatic parry.</p>

<p>But the salesman drew his sword. &ldquo;And what would that be?&rdquo; he asks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m an Apple guy, so I&rsquo;d get an iPad.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;But what if you want to do real work?&rdquo; the salesperson asks. &ldquo;Like PowerPoint.&rdquo;</p>

<p>At this moment, I&rsquo;ve got several thoughts going through my head, such as: I&rsquo;ve got a laptop and desktop for &ldquo;real work&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s more to life than &ldquo;real work.&rdquo; PowerPoint is &ldquo;real work&rdquo;? PowerPoint is not something people want to do; it&rsquo;s something they have to do once a quarter to keep upper management happy and out of their hair, so they can do what actually is <em>real work</em>. PowerPoint is the antithesis of real work.</p>

<p>But mostly I was thinking, what kind of sales strategy is this, starting an argument with a potential customer, or her significant other?</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I was drawn in. I drew my iPhone, fired up Keynote, and said, &ldquo;If I need to do that, I&rsquo;ve got Keynote.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;But that&rsquo;s not the full PowerPoint,&rdquo; he responds. He&rsquo;s right, I thought; it&rsquo;s not full of suck like PowerPoint. But I held my tongue as I remember my intent was not to participate in the trolling or any silly argument that ensued. So I said, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry, I didn&rsquo;t mean to be a part of this. Honey, did you want to look at this some more?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She replied no, so we left the store. Once out of earshot of the salesperson, I turned to her and said, &ldquo;Honey, you just trolled<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> the Microsoft Store!&rdquo;. I gave her a kiss. I was kind of proud of her geeky ploy there.</p>

<h2>Microsoft Still Loves PowerPoint</h2>

<p>I thought about this incident again recently, when I saw <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=86JMcy5OqZA&amp;feature=player_embedded">this ad</a> from Microsoft extolling the virtues of a Windows 8 tablet over an iPad. &ldquo;Sorry, I can only do one thing at a time,&rdquo; Siri says. &ldquo;I guess PowerPoint isn&rsquo;t one of those things.&rdquo;</p>

<p>What is it with you and PowerPoint, Microsoft? When I saw this ad, and read <a href="http://www.imore.com/microsoft-once-again-fails-understand-when-it-comes-tablets-windows-isnt-feature-its-liability">Rene Ritchie&rsquo;s</a> and <a href="http://www.imore.com/microsoft-once-again-fails-understand-when-it-comes-tablets-windows-isnt-feature-its-liability">John Gruber&rsquo;s</a> thoughts on it, I wondered if PowerPoint is an official Microsoft talking point when it comes to the iOS-vs-Windows debate. With just one ad an one anecdote, it could be a mere coincidence, but it sure seems like Microsoft loves PowerPoint.</p>

<p>Apple&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/videos/">ads for iPad</a> and especially <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/videos/#tv-ads-photos-every-day">iPhone</a> show people having fun and enjoying their Apple devices. Meanwhile, Microsoft touts the ability of tablets running their OS to put people to sleep in board meetings.</p>

<p>And there&rsquo;s the key different. People buy iPads and iPhones because they want to. They buy them to have fun, not &ldquo;real work.&rdquo; You can dismiss them, therefore, as &ldquo;toys&rdquo; or say they&rsquo;re only good for consuming and not creating. I&rsquo;ll disagree with those statements, in that iPads and iPhones are not only toys, and not only good for consuming, but so what if they do also make good toys? Toys are fun.</p>

<p>We buy toys because we like them and want them. We do &ldquo;real work&rdquo; because we have to. People—in particular end consumers—buy iPads not because they have to, but because they want to. Businesses buy cheap PCs so their workers can churn out PowerPoints. There&rsquo;s room for both markets, but if Microsoft is going to go after the iPad market, it had better at least try to understand it so it can market to it.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I&rsquo;ve handed down to her my old 17&#8221; MacBook Pro and iPhone 4..<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>A term I had to explain to her.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Having Fun at the Microsoft Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/05/30/microsoft-store-fun/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T12:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jimothyGator.github.io/blog/2013/05/30/microsoft-store-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Part of a man&rsquo;s inescapable duties is going to the shopping mall with his significant other. My girlfriend and I passed by the Microsoft Store, and she did a double-take. &ldquo;Wait a minute, isn&rsquo;t the Apple Store upstairs?&rdquo; she asked as she looked in the shop with white walls and evenly spaced tables with computers and gadgets on display. A Microsoft Store does, surely by no coincidence, closely resemble an Apple Store. But there are at least two obvious differences.</p>

<p>One is the four color logo out front. The second is that the Microsoft Store had few customers, in contrast to what is, at this mall at least, a perpetually packed Apple Store. There had to be at least twice as many employees as customers, and maybe three times as many.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Let&rsquo;s go in,&rdquo; she said.</p>

<p>Let me tell you a little bit about my girlfriend. When it comes to computers and technology, she&rsquo;s just an ordinary person. She has and enjoys her iPhone and iPad. But she has, until very recently, always used Windows computers, and at the time of the visit, she hadn&rsquo;t yet gotten her first Mac<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Windows is the default choice for most people, and she was no different. She doesn&rsquo;t think or care too much about operating system choices, or the companies that make them.</p>

<p>In other words, she&rsquo;s like the majority of people out there, rather than a geek opinionated about technology. That&rsquo;s my role to play in the relationship.</p>

<p>I point this out because what she did next was, honestly, quite geeky.</p>

<p>The Microsoft Store had on display, towards the front of the store, a Windows tablet; I believe it was a Samsung. This was before the release of Windows 8, so it was Windows 7 running on a touch screen. It seemed an odd fit, as the controls controls were not sized with fingers in mind, but it also came with a stylus, so if Windows is your thing, and you want a touch screen, I suppose you could make this work.</p>

<p>A salesperson in a brightly colored t-shirt with a lanyard around his neck (hmm, I swear I&rsquo;ve seen this look before) appoached. &ldquo;May I help you?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Which is better,&rdquo; my better half asks, &ldquo;this or an iPad?&rdquo;</p>

<p>As I mentioned, she already has an iPad, so this can mean only one thing: She&rsquo;s trolling at the Microsoft Store. Uh oh.</p>

<p>The salesperson starts his speil, which I honestly didn&rsquo;t pay much attention to, because though I was surprised and somewhat amused by her trolling, I decided it was best I not take a part in it. This could only turn into a mall re-enactment of a million pointless Internet arguments, and I was not in the mood.</p>

<p>She let him continue, an I recall him saying things like &ldquo;real computer&rdquo; and &ldquo;full Windows experience.&rdquo; Then she turned to me and asked, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know, honey, what do you think I should get?&rdquo; She knew what I thought. Definitely trolling.</p>

<p>Oh boy. My effort to stay out of this was being put to the test. &ldquo;Well, honey, you know what I prefer, but you do what you think is best for you.&rdquo; I tried my best at a diplomatic parry.</p>

<p>But the salesman drew his sword. &ldquo;And what would that be?&rdquo; he asks.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m an Apple guy, so I&rsquo;d get an iPad.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;But what if you want to do real work?&rdquo; the salesperson asks. &ldquo;Like PowerPoint.&rdquo;</p>

<p>At this moment, I&rsquo;ve got several thoughts going through my head, such as: I&rsquo;ve got a laptop and desktop for &ldquo;real work&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s more to life than &ldquo;real work.&rdquo; PowerPoint is &ldquo;real work&rdquo;? PowerPoint is not something people want to do; it&rsquo;s something they have to do once a quarter to keep upper management happy and out of their hair, so they can do what actually is <em>real work</em>. PowerPoint is the anthesis of real work.</p>

<p>But mostly I was thinking, what kind of sales strategy is this, starting an argument with a potential customer, or her significant other?</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I was drawn in. I drew my iPhone, fired up Keynote, and said, &ldquo;If I need to do that, I&rsquo;ve got Keynote.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;But that&rsquo;s not the full PowerPoint,&rdquo; he responds. He&rsquo;s right, I thought; it&rsquo;s not full of suck like PowerPoint. But I held my tongue as I remember my intent was not to participate in the trolling or any silly argument that ensued. So I said, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry, I didn&rsquo;t mean to be a part of this. Honey, did you want to look at this some more?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She replied no, so we left the store. Once out of earshot of the salesperson, I turned to her and said, &ldquo;Honey, you just trolled the Microsoft Store!&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>. I gave her a kiss. I was kind of proud of her geeky ploy there.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>She now uses my old 17&#8221; MacBook Pro. Her iPhone 4 is also a hand-me-down from her wonderful and attractive boyfriend.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>She wasn&rsquo;t familiar with the term &ldquo;trolling&rdquo;, so I had to explain it to her. That made this incident all the more amusing to me, since it was out of character for her.<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
